# **Gabil Gurbanov**

<u>+994 55 289 63 86</u> · ggurbanov12098@ada.edu.az · https://github.com/ggurbanov12098 Baku, Surakhani, AZ1133

Senior year Computer Science student. Enthusiastic learner in Data Science, Cyber, and Network. I am ready to utilize my education and passion to further the mission of success and improvement. To get a challenging degree at recognized universities that will allow me to further my education, experience, and abilities. Find a responsible education opportunity where I can put my training and abilities to good use while contributing to the institutions and country's success. Technologically adept, versatile programs, and advanced computer skills. Bringing forth a positive attitude of willingness and motivation to learn new skills and programs.

#### **EDUCATION**

ADA University
BS in Computer Science

Sep 2019 - May 2024

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

ABB Aug 2023 - Nov 2023

# **Network Operations Center Analyst intern**

- Analyze network and other critical infrastructure using various monitoring tools and technologies, including Wazuh, Zabbix, and Dynatrace.
- Support Active Directory services, ensuring secure and efficient user access to network resources in alignment with InfoSec industry standards.
- Respond to alerts, incidents, and service requests in a timely and efficient manner, ensuring minimal downtime for critical financial operations.
- Scripting to automate a number of NOC functions to help increase team efficiency.
- Process & update weekly and monthly NOC reports.

# BestComp Group Jun 2022 - Nov 2022 Data Analyst

- Developed datasets for model training.
- Performed Data cleaning operations.
- Developed an OCR model for license number recognition Conducted research and prepared reports on various topics related to the company's operations and industry trends.
- Trained YOLOv5 object detection model for detecting license plates.

# LANGUAGE SKILLS

- Azerbaijani (Native)
- Russian (Advanced)
- English (Advanced)

#### **ACHIEVEMENT & CERTIFICATIONS**

- Academic Excellence, honored for outstanding academic performance qualifying for the Dean's List of High Performance in ADA
- Pre-finalist in the Republican Subject Olympiad (District-City stage) in Mathematics held by the Republic of Azerbaijan Ministry of Education on 04.02.2018
- Coursera: Foundations of Cybersecurity (Google)
- Coursera: Play It Safe, Manage Security Risks (Google)
- Coursera: Connect and Protect, Networks and Network Security (Google)
- Successful completion of Embedded Systems Pro Bootcamp
- Successful completion of Python Dev Pro Bootcamp
- Achievement for completing the mandatory requirements and for outstanding performance in ADA Employability Week by ABB and ATL Tech (seperately in 2022 and 2023)

# **SKILLS**

#### **Hard Skills:**

- Programming & Scripting languages in Python, Java, JavaScript, C, Bash, PSQL
- Advanced Computer Networks, Big Data, Artificial Intelligence
- Microsoft Office tools and Cloud (Server), AWS
- Statistics and Mathematical Reasoning

### **Soft Skills:**

- Adaptation to single and team work
- Proactive troubleshooter
- Communication

#### VOLUNTEER

- ADA Innovation Center
- Baku City Circuit (Formula 1)
- "Davam" Youth Center (IT club)
- Mars Academy / RoboGames (Lego Robotics)
- ASAN Service